Contact

nigel.jp.durham@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nigeldurham (LinkedIn) nigeldurham.com (Portfolio)

Top Skills

UX Design

Neuroscience

Research

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
French (Professional Working)
German

Nigel Durham

UX Designer

San Francisco, California

Summary

Passionate designer and researcher fascinated by complex mechanical, software, or design systems. With a pedagogic and autodidactic background in neuroscientific research, fine art, and experience design, I seek to synthesize novel solutions that drive meaningful change for new or existing platforms.

Experience

BlueberryX, EventHollow User Experience Designer August 2017 - Present Brooklyn, NY

Designing simple, elegant solutions for product, web, and mobile. Incorporating user-centered design strategies, I simplify existing interfaces by leveraging intuitive design solutions.

NootBot

User Experience Researcher December 2016 - August 2017 (9 months) Brooklyn, NY

Conducted user research for a chat bot-based web application. Insights drove development of ranking and suggestion systems for in-conversation product suggestions and batching options.

Luca Dellaverson Studio
Studio Assistant
November 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 2 months)
Brooklyn, NY

Worked alongside artist developing large scale (≥ 8'x10') glass enamel sculptures. Work addressed the relationship between artist and society through the framework of continental philosophy.

Selected work can be found here: https://jacktiltongallery.com/artists/dellaverson/

Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center Research Associate October 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Greater New York City Area

As a part of a small, interdisciplinary team, implemented a translational stem cell protocol for the treatment of Parkinson's Disease. Employed complex behavioral and immunohistochemical methods to determine the efficacy of stem cell grafts in an hemi-Parkinsonian PD model.

Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai Research Associate January 2013 - January 2014 (1 year 1 month) Greater New York City Area

Categorized prefrontal and striatal abnormalities in a Shank-3 model of autism. Employed electrophysiological measures to determine changes in prefrontal-striatal synchrony during task learning and performance.

Massachusetts Institute of Technology Research Associate March 2011 - August 2011 (6 months) Cambridge, MA

Studied the effects of chronic immobilization stress on electrophysiological measures of hippocampal and amygdalar activity in rats. Investigated the role of microglial phagocytosis in stress-induced hippocampal atrophy, targeting microglial genes responding to local inflammatory cascades.

Boston University School of Medicine Research Associate June 2009 - February 2011 (1 year 9 months) Greater Boston Area

Assisted and later directed an assessment of therapeutic potential of antiepileptics and putative cognitive enhancers on deficient place cell remapping in aged rat hippocampus.

Boston University
Volunteer Research Associate
October 2008 - January 2009 (4 months)
Greater Boston Area

Assessed the expression of two IEGs, Arc and Homer, in the hippocampus of rodents undergoing a 10-odor DNMS task.

Education

General Assembly

Certificate, User Experience Design · (2018 - 2018)

California College of the Arts

Painting and Drawing, Industrial Design · (2012 - 2013)

Boston University

Bachelor of Arts (BA), with Distinction, Cum

Laude, Neuroscience · (2007 - 2010)